you offended half my wedding and I think
he's dating my wife but it sounds cool
but he says it what down south this
summer I was in Mexico City for five
days I just went by myself and never
been there before I love Mexico I think
it gets a bad rap I love the people
loved it and everybody was so scared
they would say don't go to Mexico City
man why oh it's really spread out it's
really crowded and the traffic's
horrible and the air quality is bad and
there's a lot of crime and you can't
speak English and everywhere and I was
like yeah I live in LA we just described
every day in my life for the last 20
years who don't tell me is that a lot of
Mexicans there too what's that like gee
I hope I understand the food what is
this a taco am I saying that right
taco is that interesting
it's no big deal tell you why you live
in LA you go to Mexico dad a big culture
shock you know it's a culture shock to
me now Vermont that's a culture shock
Alabama just a bunch of people walking
around speaking English and poor and
ranch dressing all over everything
what's the gringo got to do get it cold
horchata up in here what else was I had
a far trip last year I went to Australia
anybody been there yeah that's fun boy I
love Australians they're just tan
Canadians who surf and again no one
hates them they get away with anything
Australian guy these are the least
politically correct people you've ever
met in your life they just say anything
they want blah they don't care and they
get away with it with that cool accent
here's something an Australian guys
never done before telling a filthy joke
in public never done it this bad just
says it it just covers it up I know
where he's made that's fine then I guess
he offended half my wedding and I think
he's dating my wife but it sounds cool
but he says it learned how to speak
Australian when I was there it's very
simple all you do is just shorten every
word
breakfast is brekkie mosquitoes are
mozzies sunglasses are Sunny's and board
shorts or forties is shortened every
word except the names of their towns
which are 85 letters long all right boys
we got one set for tomorrow eat your
prank but on your board ease where your
son ease and look out for the mozzies
cuz we're going to the town of boom
b-boom b-boom leap on go it's just south
to jumper one but Kasia CooCoo no
worries me Australians get around I see
them all over the world the only people
I see more travel there's the Germans
boy I've never not run into one German
somewhere you right there see there's
always one always one two of them oh man
you guys travel everywhere right I've
never been to a veteran you haven't been
and and they'd like to get off the grid
boy you could go to the most remote
place of the world hack through four
days of Borneo jungle off the grid off
the GPS off the map you come across some
hidden Cove with its overgrown and you
think to yourself wow I'm probably the
first human being that ever set foot on
this spot and the second lay down your
backpack and naked German couple walks
out good and ty
where'd you come from we've been here
for three weeks Weil German we have 47
weeks of paid vacation a year for those
Germans love getting naked outdoors in
public boy whoops we see your body of
water those shorts are down it's good to
be natural outside yeah yeah sir this is
Disney waterpark if you could just take
those shorts up your hair you're scaring
the children
I don't want to put too much pressure on
you because I just had the greatest gig
I've ever done the most rewarding I just
performed for the troops and it's
amazing just getting there that's the
hardest part about going to perform for
the troops you have to just get there I
had to go all the way from Los Angeles
to San Diego and whoo rush hour huh Wow
for giving out medals come on now
they're so young that's the thing when
you when you meet them in person the
troops that just you forget how young
they are they're just kids there was so
enthusiastic and grateful we were there
and they wanted to pay me and I wouldn't
take it just I just took some cookies
these were Girl Scout troops did I
mention that our personal I always bury
the lead on that sorry still heroes
every one of them every one of them
heroes
I admire anybody who joins the military
I you tried I you know went down there
and army doctors told me I had cowardice
so
apparently that's not what they're
looking for in the service these days
told me to stick with comedy so I do I
know when your comedian get asked the
same questions all the time and I think
the honest question I always get asked
is say you're comedian huh yeah like it
yeah
Oh we'll be up here if I don't want to
be here generally this is not one of
those jobs your parents force you into
never here a guy here complaining yeah I
wanted to be a doctor but my old man
comedy comedy comedy comedy comedy
comedy comedy I was the only kid Little
League with big floppy clown shoes X my
parents are pretty cool is what I do
which is odd because they're smart
they're teachers we need good teachers
I've had some bad ones yeah their
teachers here yeah god bless it
we need good teachers I've had fifth
grade I had a teacher she would use big
words and use them wrong then one day
that was in a clip so we all wanted to
run out and go see the Eclipse and she
stops us at the door she goes don't look
right at the Sun don't look straight at
the Sun you'll burn your rectum
so lady I think you're looking out the
wrong eye five up top all right yeah
I'll find my own way to the principal's
office thank you very much I know where
it is I was at the principal's office a
lot cuz I had an attitude problem and
Here I am yeah my parents taught science
which is my worst subject ever but I got
an a on every science project why I had
help you always know the kids who had
help because everybody else's walk
around little paper cups with seeds
growing out of them and cheap clay
volcanoes I'm over in the corner in a
lab coat doing gene therapy
Mike did your parents help you bill
these are my monkeys parents but if your
parents teach they I was trying to sneak
little lessons to you all day when you
don't know you're learning this happened
to me is a true story my friends and I
were about eight years old found the
frog on the side of the house showed it
to my dad and to give us a little
science lesson on the spot he dissected
it in the front yard looking back now
kind of weird but at a time really cool
an eight-year-old boy with guts didn't
think it was great I learned a lot that
day namely that my dad had a little
reputation in the neighborhood after
that was a long time before anybody's
dog pooped in our yard again
that's it fluffy do your business oh not
that house holy cow dr. Frankenstein in
that house my mama's a research chemist
she actually worked on a cure for cancer
which is hard to live up to I'll be
honest I was calling her from the road
hey mom how's it going oh really good
we're doing gene transfer experiments
with the simian virus hoping an isolated
DNA working a vaccine
what are you doing Mike I'm at the
Chuckle barn in Toledo
I get free chicken wings how's my
monkeys comedies brought me a lot of
places emerging from the Midwest Chicago
and hey you two clap those frozen hands
go ahead I moved out to California still
not used to Hollywood I still can't get
used to the people there's a guy in my
gym and works out everyday in sunglasses
it's pretend just right if I see you
working out every day in sunglasses
there better be a dog in front of you on
the treadmill
that's my heart rate boy because it is
that's my impression of a blind guy shot
my eyes actor
acting there's a tough gig boy that's a
tough one and one acting job last year
one paid acting gig and it was a
non-speaking role in an animated film I
played a tree everybody's broke in
Hollywood but no one was the act broke
you have these friends that are broke
snobs you know people like that they got
no money but they'll turn their nose up
at free stuff like they're too good for
it
and a friend like that drives me nuts
I'll go hey man I got us free tickets
for that concert you wanted to see free
tickets he goes yeah where are the seats
where the seats well apparently they're
in the ungrateful bastard section where
this seat
see where the seats are there's 30 miles
closer to the stage than your house
that's all you need to know somebody
told me when I got into this business I
should incorporate myself for my taxes I
should be a one-person corporation so I
did that became a one-person corporation
and then I was between gigs one year and
I tried to get unemployment and they
told me to get unemployment I was gonna
have to fire myself I never fired anyone
or been fired now we got to do both I
didn't want to do it but then it took a
second look at my financial performance
from last year and I think I had it
coming
turns out I was the weak link in my
corporation clearly I had to go so I
called myself into the home office in
the kitchen apparently there been rumors
going through the hallways that
something was going to him
rumors of me showing up in pajamas
sexual harassment they can't prove that
though
then I did it I let myself go I didn't
take it well I'll be honest
I'm not proud of this but on the way out
I stole some stuff
I thought I earned it go back on the
road to make money there's no place I
won't play paid a retirement home not
too long ago things are looking up
there's a 95 year old guy there 95 sharp
is attack he's a stockbroker 95 year old
stockbroker first stock he ever bought
fire that's an old man bought the wheel
at 26 cents a share he did very well he
was there with his third wife who was 75
yeah this guy's robbing a 75 year old
cradle and I asked him I was fascinated
I said how do you get the ladies at your
age you know as hey as a man the longer
you live the better your odds get it's
true
I saw the ratio in the retirement home
in a man and woman ratio if you're a
single guy in a retirement home you're
fighting off the ladies and if he can
drive at night holy cow
Brad Pitt with a walker going in there
man I'm feeling aged already I'm
starting I got this got my first pair of
reading glasses whoa yeah yeah I got
them yeah sure
it's a proud day in a man's life go down
to the drugstore get the three pack that
used to mean something a lot more fun
when I was a younger man no nope got
them all over the house right there
fellas I don't care how cool you think
you are these will take all the cool
right out of your game right there I
don't care how smooth you think you are
these will you put these on and your
back starts to hurt immediately hello
ladies I know I don't know what happened
it's just like I woke up one day and I'm
doing the extendo-arm it's like my
eyeballs had a meeting while I was
asleep it's like we're done reading this
close to our face we're gonna I'm in a
dark restaurant I gonna put the menu and
a selfie stick with a flashlight cousin
never saw James Bond pulled he's out in
the movie even though it was like 70 and
some of those all right Goldfinger I got
your plans for
nuclear animation come on annihilation
there we go
can that be cool with these first night
I had him I went to my local restaurant
I've known the owner for years he's an
older guy and he saw me but Amani what
hahaha
you finally got the magic glasses huh I
said we're gonna magic that help me see
it he goes oh no those glasses have
superpowers said really said yeah when
you put them on you become invisible to
young women he's not wrong you want to
feel the old technology that'll make you
feel old it just goes too fast I get a
new phone I got an asking 8 year old how
it works
I don't think all improvements are good
though all technology like this this is
our my hotel room key this is this is
what we get at every hotel now is this
is this an improvement over the actual
metal key they used to work what 100
percent of the time
what do you you check into a new hotel
how many swipes on average does it take
for you to get in the first time my
over-under is about 700 swipes it never
works it's always the same scenario I'm
exhausted I just want to go to bed been
traveling all day as I move finally
we're here but red flipping it over
rubbing rabbit's foot on it nothing
works
now you've stuck with your bags in the
hallway you gotta go take the death
march back down to the lobby to another
furious people in line holding their
cards what happens when you get up there
they flip it on you like you're the bad
guy but you're the idiot yeah my keys
not working hmm did you swipe it more
than once no didn't think of that
no I'm a one-and-done kind of guy
my car doesn't start on the first try
just get out and walk to Poughkeepsie
that's how I roll I swipe it more than
once yes I swiped at a million times it
doesn't work this is my favorite one do
you have a phone in your pocket yes it's
21st century we'll have phones in our
pockets babies have phones in their
diapers we all have a phone
you're amazing key can't handle a phone
then I thought about it I got this giant
phone coz my eyes are going huge screen
and now she's telling me there's enough
radiation kicking off this thing that
screwing up the key card so of course
where do I keep it all day every day
like a genius right there next to my
crouch just you just microwaving my
privates all day long idiot
probably got two lonely chromosomes left
down there wiling away the end of their
days watching big-screen movies in my
pants
I know if all technology's good we try
to protect everybody from technology and
then we go overboard would protect the
kids too much do you know that my niece
can't go outside unless it's a playdate
I remember my playdates growing up get
outside all right
this I better learn how to make friends
some of the technology is good if it
helps you you saved your life you know I
had to put in a car seat for her that's
three hours of my life I'll never get
back
I don't remember my dad doing this I try
to think about how I grew up and this is
no joke me my brother and sister on long
car rides used to fold the seat down in
a station wagon and play twister at 70
miles an hour
just three tangled projectiles ready to
rock it through the windshield at any
moment my dad's driving with one knee
taking a turn it was a right-hand read I
got it I got it I got it
how are any of us left standing I don't
know
well the pregnant women in my
neighborhood they don't leave the house
without a surgical mask on so I guess
couldn't hurt but I don't know is that
necessary see pictures of your
grandmother just eight months pregnant
cigarette martini on the back of a
motorcycle
somehow we survived I don't know thought
by this point my life I'd want children
and yeah I like it when they're little
is just a thought having a teenager
that's what scares me
some punk with a bad attitude who thinks
I'm a nerd I don't need that I'm gonna
hand over all my money to someone who
doesn't want to be seen with me in
public I'll call my agent but they say
is a man you can have kids at any age
don't wear any age all right yeah but do
you want to say Oh Mick Jagger just had
a kid at 73 oh well good for Mick
I'm sure him and his household staff of
12 will be great parents a little
different for the rest of us yeah first
of all I don't think Mick even knows he
had a kid you just woke up one morning I
think I thought I heard a baby in the
castle last night
yes make that's your new child cool it's
no clue don't know if I want to be super
old dad then I thought about it maybe
it's not so bad
probably got a lot in common with a baby
for the same amount of hair you both
like soft food then you're on the same
nap schedule it'll work out so much
birth control on the market though this
is a birth control patch for women that
looks incredibly like the nicotine patch
which means if the practical joke
possibilities are endless
imagine that your buddies trying to quit
smoking you switch up his patch on him
he thinks he's getting his nicotine dose
Riley's gonna daily estrogen hormone
cocktail just pump that's good clean fun
right there Dave I thought you quit
smoking there I'm on the patch I don't
think it's working I cry a lot more my
chest is swollen and tender I don't get
it
I don't smoke I try to protect my lungs
I had a little scare in Alaska this
summer I was working up there and it's
beautiful up there just like the nature
it's amazing and went on a hike and
after about 15 minutes and I was like
wheezing and I couldn't get it then I
realized it's because I've lived in LA
so long my lungs can't handle all the
fresh air in the air up there what do
you call this oxygen oh man ooh Eddy go
suck a tailpipe just to feel normal
fired up oh yeah that's the stuff ya
know just like home Alaska's a wild
place man it's interesting kind of
person that moves up there you know who
moves to Alaska people who think Idaho
is too diverse that's
couldn't handle that fast-paced gogo
Montana lifestyle anymore I had to had
to get away got to have the salmon when
you're up there they don't give you a
choice they're just jamming it down
you're throwing every five minutes have
some salmon don't boom don't forget to
try some salmon take some home with you
have some salmon wait relax I'm not a
grizzly back off been here a week I had
an 80 different ways grilled fried
poached spread on a bagel smoked I mean
I smoked it just for something different
anything in every restaurant up there
pushes it on you're like you can't get
it at the next restaurant and the next
one after that and our special today is
the salmon oh you don't say don't tell
me was it the special the last 364 days
- did you fly it in special or did you
just you know go outside bend over in a
puddle and pick one up
I tripped over 3 salmon walking in this
place it's good but it's not special up
here you know it's a special up here at
decent burrito get on that I was up in
Alaska working I was up in Canada a lot
this summer I love Canada it's a
beautiful place nicest people in the
world I was in the Vancouver Airport I
asked the guy Canadian guy to look over
my bags while I went to the bathroom
came back he had ironed my shirts
nicest people
why aren't they nice I made my gosh oh
that nobody hates them that's why
they're so nice around the world that
Canadian passport is like a
get-out-of-jail-free card I asked the
guy why do you put Canadian flags all
over everything you own we don't want
people to think we're Americans but I
get it
you know kidnappers will let you go if
they find out you're Canadian send a
ransom for the American bad news boss
turns out he's Canadian what let him go
can't kidnap a Canadian we're terrorists
we're not animals
what's the world gonna say besides what
do we get for him loonies
Tony's syrup helmets hockey sticks who
cares I love going up there Canadians we
can be care about curling every four
years in the Olympics seen this crazy
sport shuffleboard on ice with rocks and
brooms what the heck am i watching and
yet after ten minutes every time I'm
shouting at the TV sweeping sweeping
this guy sweeps like my grandmother
sport came from Scotland I don't know
how bored they were around that ice
fishing hole
furgus slide with that rocky there's too
much snow well get the brooms land
[Laughter]
[Applause]
we gotta send this is a new country had
the national dish up in Canada poutine
have you had that ah man delicious if
you don't know what poutine is think of
the last thing your doctor whatever
recommend you eat and then pour gravy on
it that's what it's just a big pile of
french fries with cheese curds and beef
gravy yeah if you get the deluxe version
they just sprinkle the shredded remains
of your cardiologist report right on it
this is created and Quebec by
descendants of the French the French who
created like fine cuisine what happened
on that ride over the Atlantic the
shipwreck with all the cookbooks on it
[Applause]
[Laughter]
don't think I'll ever stop traveling
though although the airlines might beat
it out of me we take so much abuse from
airlines we couldn't take from any other
business oversold flights over so yeah
we're just so too many sorry what what
other business that transaction would
that be cool I want to buy this candy
bar okay that's a dollar here's my
dollar where's my candy well you know
what's the darndest thing we're out
[Music]
what yeah we just sold to many sorry but
I gave you money yes you did thank you
very much
when do I get my candy well the next
Snickers truck comes by in about 4 hours
there's any leftover on that one you'll
get one of them
but until then grab a magazine go sit
over there like an idiot for four hours
and don't forget to join our frequent
idiot program
[Applause]
security that that's the worst right cuz
it's never the same at any Airport it's
never consistent in the same day I could
go through one airport they'll make me
take my shoes off my felt my wallet and
give me an MRI in a colonoscopy and the
same day I could go through another
airport I could be wearing a suit of
armor it's like I'm glad all right
katroo no consistency toughest one
toughest security ever had Israel I
don't know if you have a baby you've
been there oh man four hours four hours
in security ask me all these questions
search my bags went through my clothes
they took up my phone and looked at the
photos on my phone
and now that I know they can look
through your photos you gotta put one
[__] shot of yourself in there just
slide it in there with the tourist shots
you know right between the Wailing Wall
and the Jerusalem you just coming out
isn't out of the hotel showers
I can't be illegal right picture
yourself on your phone I didn't tell you
to look at it don't judge me by my
screensaver guess if I want a decent
relationship I have to stay home at some
point
I don't know after 20 years of bad
relationships I'm starting to think I
might be part of the problem now that's
just a therapy talking my ex told me I
had intimacy issues as if that's any of
her business I'm starting to data as I
get older I have to date people who
already had kids which is a little
that's a tough one you can't rush that
you can't meet those kids too early yeah
I had this one it was like two dates and
she already said she had two little boys
and she went I'm gonna take the kids to
the carnival this weekend you want to go
I was like wow no it sounds awful I'm
not anti kid but you know who am I to
these kids I'm just some guy they don't
know me I can't discipline them if
they're acting up at the carnival they
get down from there you're gonna get
hurt you're not my dad you know what
you're right
go ahead stand up in the tilt-a-whirl I
want to see how this goes
kind of curious myself to see how this
is gonna play out I've dated all types
went out with a vegan and that was once
I think I couldn't figure out what they
could eat or not
I couldn't as far as I could tell a
vegan could have like chickpeas and
cotton that was it
and have some hummus and wash it down
with a tube sock or something all my
friends have kids do you feel left out
at parties you know when they're almost
everybody's got their phones out showing
photos of their kids you know so if you
feel left out at those points just do
what I do and just show them photos of
single-person stuff that they can't do
anymore
just go this is me sleeping in on the
weekend yeah this is me and my white
carpet yeah well this is my favorite one
this is me leaving a bad relationship
and still keeping my house
sweet equity it grow so fast
[Laughter]
keys to find someone with the same sense
of humor is you that's an important
thing and humor is an effective way to
get yourselves out of uncomfortable
situations case in point is a true story
and there's time to use humor when not
to and when you can like say airport
security bad time and meeting dates
parents for the first time
another bad time hence this story I went
to this woman's house to pick her up
it's our first date and she had just
gotten divorced and had to move back in
with her parents which happens I don't
care whatever but she's running late and
he meet her parents and I have to sit in
the living room with her parents
watching TV you know like prom night
it's just really awkward and you know
they were nice enough but weird and
they're watching TV there's the TV in
the room there's a movie on and this is
a romantic movie a very romantic movie
and this uncomfortable scene comes up
with two men yes and it's very tense and
weird in the room kind of like now
and I'm sitting there and no one knows
what to say it's just such a weird vibe
and it's just tense and weird and I just
thought to myself what better time for a
joke they didn't see it that way because
it's very weird tense and awkward in the
room and these guys are on the TV and I
just go wow that's a that takes me back
not a good idea folks you guys have been
fantastic thank you so much thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
you